<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guests on Long Tales of Science</title>
    <link>https://nicole-brewer.github.io/long-tales-of-science/guest/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guests on Long Tales of Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nicole-brewer.github.io/long-tales-of-science/guest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Elizabeth Aslinger</title>
      <link>https://nicole-brewer.github.io/long-tales-of-science/guest/easlinger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicole-brewer.github.io/long-tales-of-science/guest/easlinger/</guid>
      <description>Elizabeth Aslinger completed her PhD in mathematical and computational psychology and MS in clinical psychology at Purdue University. As an undergraduate, she studied neurobiology and philosophy of science at Yale University, ultimately graduating with a BA in the interdisciplinary track of political science. After college, she worked as a learning center teacher and led psychoeducational groups in a psychiatric hospital while coauthoring a chapter about neuroscience methodology with Scott Lilienfeld at Emory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hellen Wellons</title>
      <link>https://nicole-brewer.github.io/long-tales-of-science/guest/hwellons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicole-brewer.github.io/long-tales-of-science/guest/hwellons/</guid>
      <description>Helen Wellons recently retired from her Senior Scientific Advisor role with ExxonMobil Research and Engineering Company after a 30-year career.
Helen, and her spouse Michael, joined Mobil in January, 1990 after receiving Ph.Ds. in Chemical Engineering from Purdue University. She started her career in the Pilot Plant Automation Group, developing supervisory control systems for pilot plants. She then worked in Applied Fluid Mechanics, designing cold flow experiments to develop models for lubes and hydroconversion processes and helped to build the organization’s early Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD) capabilities to address refinery challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sarah Wellons</title>
      <link>https://nicole-brewer.github.io/long-tales-of-science/guest/swellons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicole-brewer.github.io/long-tales-of-science/guest/swellons/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Sarah Wellons is a postdoctoral fellow at the Center for Interdisciplinary Exploration and Research in Astrophysics (CIERA) at Northwestern University. She earned her PhD in Astronomy and Astrophysics with a secondary field in Computational Science and Engineering from Harvard University in 2017. Dr. Wellons studies the physics of galaxy formation using massively parallel hydrodynamical cosmological simulations. Her work focuses on the most massive galaxies which formed in the first few billion years after the Big Bang, and on the physics of how star formation is regulated in such galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bilel Hadri</title>
      <link>https://nicole-brewer.github.io/long-tales-of-science/guest/bhadri/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicole-brewer.github.io/long-tales-of-science/guest/bhadri/</guid>
      <description>Computational scientist with more than 10 years experience in HPC along with more than 5 years in leadership computing centers. Interested in monitoring, analyzing and bechmarking applications to effectively and efficiently use supercomputers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Le Mai Weakley</title>
      <link>https://nicole-brewer.github.io/long-tales-of-science/guest/lmweakley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicole-brewer.github.io/long-tales-of-science/guest/lmweakley/</guid>
      <description>Le Mai Weakley received her PhD in Mathematics from Indiana University in 2013. She is part of the Research Applications and Deep Learning team at Indiana University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nancy Wilkins-Diehr</title>
      <link>https://nicole-brewer.github.io/long-tales-of-science/guest/nwilkins-diehr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicole-brewer.github.io/long-tales-of-science/guest/nwilkins-diehr/</guid>
      <description>Nancy has been at the San Diego Supercomputer Center since 1993, retiring in 2019 having held a variety of management positions. Nancy&amp;rsquo;s particular expertise is in the development of web interfaces to high performance computing systems, data collections, instruments and other resources fundamental to many of today&amp;rsquo;s research endeavors. Beginning with the National Science Foundation&amp;rsquo;s TeraGrid Science Gateways program in 2005, she has led many programs that support the democratization of access to high end resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rocío Carratalá Sáez</title>
      <link>https://nicole-brewer.github.io/long-tales-of-science/guest/rcsaez/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicole-brewer.github.io/long-tales-of-science/guest/rcsaez/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Rocío Carratalá Sáez received a B.Sc. Degree in Computational Mathematics by Universitat Jaume I (UJI) of Castellón (Spain) in 2015, M.Sc. Degree in Parallel and Distributed Computing by Universitat Politècnica de València (Spain) in 2016, and Ph.D. in Computer Science by UJI in 2021. She is currently an Assistant Professor at Universidad de Valladolid (UVa) in the Department of Computer Science. Her main research interest is High Performance Computing, focused on the parallelization of linear algebra operations to enable optimal executions in high performance and heterogeneous systems.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
